MARUTHA DURAI

maruthai.malvoi@gmail.com

+91-8667245372

♀Chennai, India

ABOUT ME 👋:

Highly-skilled Programmer with 4 years experience in SDLC and web application development. Advanced knowledge of FrontEnd frameworks and JavaScript. Logical and results-driven, dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused websites for customers with various business objectives. Possess good knowledge in Data structures & Algorithms and excellent problem-solving skills.

SKILLS X:

- → Front-End: ReactJS, Angular 6, NextJS, Redux, Mobx, Mobx State tree.
- → Back-End: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Django, MongoDB, Postgersql, SQL
- → Languages: Javascript, TypeScript, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SASS, Data Structure & Algorithms.
- → Tools: GIT, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Jira, Vs Code

WORK EXPERIENCE ::

Viasat India, Chennai— Software Engineer III (OCT 2021 - PRESENT)

Developing feature rich network montioring application. Which helps to monitor the connectivity, health status of various network devices from a single place. (Technology used: Angular 6, Python, Django, MySQL)

→ Being responsible for end to end software life cycle, handled all the phases of application like Database management, API & UI development and deploying the application. Implemented a network map which shows the various status of network devices like routers and switches connected across the location using D3js.

Cognizant Technology, Chennai—Programmer Analyst (JAN 2021 - OCT 2021)

Involved in front end development of next generation E-Learning platform OneReader.(Technology used: ReactJs, Mobx, Material UI, Webpack)

→ Notable contribution on user navigation, last location, audio book, theming modules. Develop user interface components and features using React functional and Material ui. Created reusable React components and managed application state with Mobx State Tree, Implemented Snapshot testing using Jest for React project along with Enzyme test utilities.

Infosys Ltd, Chennai— Systems Engineer (FEB 2018 - DEC 2020)

Developed an application to monitor and control employee access management for a US based banking organization. (Technology used: ReactJs, Material UI, SCSS, Redux)

→ Developed a form page to create a filter which can be saved and executed as per schedule to get the employees matching condition Implemented functionality to monitor and revoke access granted to a group of employees.Implemented application wide themes using custom material theme modules.

EDUCATION .:

- → Kongu Engineering College, Erode B.E Electronics & Instrumentation (2013 2017).
- → Attended 6 month internship as a FullStack developer(MERN) in IIT Madras incubated company.